iversity.org 2015-12-25

# iversity - Privacy

iversity.org is an Internet based platform (“Platform”) run by iversity GmbH (“iversity”) for the use of so called Massive Open Online Courses (“MOCC”) also via mobile Internet. The Platform aims primarily at students who would like to enroll in courses of universities other than their actual course of study. But also anybody else interested in further academic studies can join the Platform’s courses (“User”). The operation of the Platform requires the collecting, processing and use of personal data. The data concerned is mostly such data which you as User uploaded yourself onto the Platform and make available to iversity, other Users and/or the general internet public. You create your own profile with information and photos of yourself as well as other content. You exchange views with other Users, write messages to them, provide content for discussion forums and/or for all Users and comment on their contents, etc. Please provide information about yourself wisely. iversity can and will protect your data technically – however please protect yourself by the self-conscious use of the Internet as a medium. 

To some extent, iversity collects, processes and uses the data for its own specific purposes. iversity sets a high value on privacy and data security and complies with all the relevant data privacy provisions, in particular, with the Federal Data Protection Act (Bundesdatenschutzgesetz, “BDSG”) and the Telemedia Act (Telemediengesetz). The following privacy policy will explain in detail for what purposes and to which extent personal data is collected, processed and used on the Platform. By registering to the Platform on its website or login over the account of Facebook or a comparable network you give your consent to iversity with regard to the following procedures of data collection, data processing and data use as described in detail below. You can withdraw your consent at any time. The withdrawal should be directed to 

iversity GmbH  
Berliner Straße 33,  
16321 Bernau bei Berlin. 

The withdrawal can also be sent to the following email address:  

Additionally, you can download the privacy policy as a PDF document. 

**1\. Collection, processing and use of personal data**

iversity collects, processes and uses personal data when you register to use the Platform (so called “inventory data”, see sec 1.1), use the Platform (so called “usage data”, see sec. 1.2) or upload content and data onto the Platform after registration (so called “content data”, see sec. 1.3). In accordance with sec. 3 para. 1 BDSG personal data means any information concerning the personal or material circumstances of an identified or identifiable individual. 

**1.1. Data during registration (Inventory Data)**

iversity solely collects, processes and uses the following data obtained during the registration process on the website: 

  * first and last name,  

  * your e-mail address by which you can be reached,  

  * a password for the future access to the Platform.  

If you log on to the Platform over your Facebook account, iversity collects, processes and uses your Facebook authentication information, e.g., your User name, encrypted access information, and other data accessible via your Facebook account, e.g., your name, your profile picture, your country, your home town, your e-mail address, your date of birth, your sex, the names, profile pictures and networks of your friends.  
The name is part of your profile and is therefore visible to other registered Users on the Platform. However, your e-mail address and password remain of course confidential and cannot be viewed by third parties. 

**1.2 Usage Data**

When using the Platform the following usage data will be collected, processed and used: 

1.2.1 Logfiles 

When you visit the pages on iversity.org access data is submitted by your web browser which is stored by iversity in the automated log files, known as server logs. These log files contain the following information: 

  * IP address of the computer,  

  * date, time, status, amount of data transferred and the website from which you came to the requested page (referrer),  

  * information on product and version of the browser (User agent), operating system, language settings.  

1.2.2 Cookies 

As part of the website of the Platform, iversity uses cookies. Cookies are small files that are stored on your hard drive and which allow iversity to gain certain pieces of information. 

  * Via a so-called session cookie iversity receives on the one hand the session ID of the User. This is a unique cryptographic identifier to authenticate the Users. On the other hand, this cookie helps to store form data which is needed across multiple pages. At the end of a session, the cookie is removed from the browser.  

  * Another cookie stores the currently selected language by the User in case it was explicitly selected by the User. At the end of a session the cookie is removed from the browser.  

If you want to prevent the use of cookies you can do this by selecting your browser settings in a way to prevent the acceptance and storage of new cookies. In order to find out in detail how this works with your browser you can for example consult the help function of your browser. However, without session and secure cookies you cannot or only partially use the services of the Platform. It is therefore advisable to allow cookies. 

1.2.3 Web analytics 

You can always object to the data collection, processing and use according to this sec. 1.2.3. 

a) iversity uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google Inc. of 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA ("Google”). Google Analytics uses 'cookies', which are text files placed on your computer, to help the web team analyse how Users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website will generally be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. In case of activation of a IP-anonymisation, Google will reduce your IP address within the member states of the European Union and other member States to the Treaty on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases, the full IP-address will be transmitted to a server of Google in the United States and be reduced there. In assignment of the operator of this website Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and Internet usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google's behalf.  
Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website. You may also deactivate Google Analytics by installing a so called browser-input-group-addon, which is provided by Google under the following address: <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en>.  
More information on Google Inc. and Google Analytics can be found here: <http://www.google.com/analytics/terms.en.html>. Google’s privacy policy can be found here: <http://www.google.com/intl/de/privacy/privacy-policy.html>. Please note that this website extended Google Analytics for the code “gat._anonymezlp();” to ensure an anonymised recording of IP-addresses (IP masking). 

b) On the landing page and the blog of the website of the Platform iversity uses plugins of the network Facebook (e.g., the "Like Button") owned by Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304 , USA. Our respective websites are marked with the respective button. If you open our websites which include such a plugin, your browser will connect directly to the servers of Facebook. The contents of the plugin originate from Facebook Inc. and are transmitted directly to your browser and displayed accordingly on our site, without us being able to alter the contents of the plugin.  
In case you are registered onto Facebook or visited a Facebook page or other pages with Facebook content recently, Facebook Inc. may understand from the information transmitted to the server of Facebook Inc. which of our web sites you have visited and associate this information to a Facebook account. Furthermore, if you want to actively use Facebook plugins (e.g., press the Like button) corresponding information from your browser will be directly transmitted to Facebook Inc. without us having any influence over that process. For detailed information on how and to what extent the Facebook Inc. collects, processes and uses relevant data, please refer to the privacy policies of Facebook Inc. which can be found under [www.facebook.com/policy.php](http://www.facebook.com/policy.php). There, you can also find information on how to protect your privacy. To prevent Facebook Inc. from collecting information about you during the visit of the Platform you can log out of Facebook before visiting our web pages and delete existing cookies from Facebook Inc. from your browser. 

c) On the web sites of iversity plugins of the short message service Twitter Inc., 795 Folsom St., Suite 600, San Francisco, CA 94107, USA, are used ("tweet" button). When you visit our websites via the corresponding "tweet" button, the plugin establishes a direct connection between your browser and the Twitter servers. Twitter receives the information that you have visited our site using your IP address and may associate this information with your Twitter account. If you click on the "tweet" button while you are logged into your Twitter account you can link content on our pages with your Twitter profile. Thus, it is possible for Twitter Inc. to associate a visit to our sites with your user account. iversity has no influence on the transmission and processing of any data by Twitter. For more information on data processing at Twitter, please refer to the privacy policy statement on <http://twitter.com/privacy>. To prevent Twitter from associating your visit to the Platform with your Twitter account please log out of your Twitter account before visiting the Platform. 

d) The websites of the Platform use the “+1″ button of the social network Google Plus, which is operated by Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, United States (“Google”). If you open a webpage of the Platform which contains a “+1″ button, your browser creates a direct connection to the Google servers. In doing so, the browser transmit to a Google server which of our websites you visited. The “+1” button is not used to detect your Internet visits in general. Google does not permanently record your browser history and does not evaluate your visit on a webpage with a “+1” button in any other way. Google will store the data about your visit for about two weeks for system maintenance and error recovery purposes. Such data is not associated with individual profiles, user names or URLs and will not be transmitted to us. If you are logged in to Google Plus and click on the “+1” button Google receives information about your Google profile, recommended URL, your IP-address and other browser related information. If you take back your +1 these information will be deleted. If you made your Google Plus profile publicly available your “+1” may be displayed together with your profile name and your profile picture or at other places on the websites and advertisements on the Internet. To prevent Google from collecting and using data as described please log off from Google Plus before visiting our website. For further information on the collecting and use of data by Google, your respective rights and possibilities to protect your privacy please see <http://www.google.com/intl/de/+/policy/+1button.html>. 

e) iversity.org uses Google AdWords conversion tracking. This service provided by Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043 USA, ("Google") will place cookies (small text files) on your computer when you visit iversity.org by clicking on a Google advertisement. These cookies are valid up to 90 days and are not used for identification of individual users, but Google and iversity.org are able to track that a user has been directed by Google advertisement. Conversion cookies help to generate statistics for Google AdWords customers by supplying them with information about the total number of users who have clicked on the Google advertisement. AdWords customers do not receive any information which would personally identify the users. If you do not wish to participate in the tracking process, you can change your browser setting to generally deactivate cookies. You can also deactivate cookies for Google conversion tracking by setting your browser to block cookies from the domain “googleadservices.com”.

f) Facebook Conversion Tracking: After your agreement, a "conversion pixels" of Facebook Inc., 1602 S. California Ave, Palo Alto VA 94304, USA ("Facebook") will be placed in your browser. By using this conversion pixel, we are able to understand how our marketing measures work and how we can improve our product accordingly. The collected data is anonymous to us. This means that we are neither able to track users nor receive information about a user's Facebook account. As Facebook is able to save and process your user information, your data might be used according to Facebook's Data Use Policy: <http://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/>. Users must be over 13 years old to be allowed to enter this agreement.

1.3 Data of uploaded content (Content Data) 

In addition to the inventory and usage data there is also data which is created by you as a User in the course of using the Platform. This includes all the data that you upload yourself voluntarily in your profile (e.g., your photo, CV or details on your previous university / faculty, contact information, etc.) or upload to other locations in your personal space (e.g., your texts, publications) or make available elsewhere (e.g., news, comments, materials, etc.). iversity does not actively collect, process or use such data. Furthermore, it is to your own discretion whether or not you provide information and to what extent the information you provide is accessible to certain Users.  
Moreover, iversity collects, processes and uses data regarding the respective course you are participating in as well as your progress with the help of your results in exams. Aside its own functions iversity offers third party functionalities in the form of apps clearly marked as such. iversity is not responsible for these offers and does not have any active influence on them in any way. Any contracts resulting from third party apps are concluded only between the User and the third party, governed by the provisions of the respective provider. For further details regarding the data collection, data processing and data use by these services please refer to the respective data privacy policies of the respective provider. 

**2\. Purposes of data collection, data processing and data use**

**2.1 Inventory Data**

2.1.1 General use of inventory data 

iversity requires and uses your data solely to adhere to its existing contractual relationships with you, that is to manage your user account, to perform potential billing procedures and if necessary to contact you. 

2.1.2 Use of your e-mail address 

iversity uses your e-mail address in order to contact you with regard to your user account and to send you the editorial newsletter and / or notifications about modifications or upgradings of iversity’s services and / or other Platform related messages, provided that you agreed to the receipt of such a newsletter beforehand. You may always unsubscribe from this newsletter at any time, either by sending us an e-mail to [newsletter@iversity.org](mailto:newsletter@iversity.org), by clicking on the appropriate link provided at the end of each newsletter or by deactivating the receipt in your account settings.  
Regarding the fact that the newsletter may contain information about new features of the Platform you can object to the use of your e-mail address for the receipt of the newsletter separately. In order to do this, please send an e-mail to: [newsletter@iversity.org](mailto:newsletter@iversity.org). 

2.1.3 Transmission of inventory data to third parties 

iversity does not transmit your inventory data to third parties. Exceptions apply, 

  * when and where it is necessary to enforce existing contractual relationships or any claims we are entitled to,  

  * if iversity is legally obliged or committed in accordance with a court ruling or  

  * when it comes to requests from governmental institutions, particularly law enforcement and regulatory authorities, if and only to the extent necessary to prevent threats to public safety and order and to prosecute crimes.  

iversity is also committed to the scientific exchange. Accordingly, iversity enables selected academic institutions to evaluate public content and anonymised User data of the Platform. Moreover, iversity transmits data (inventory and content data) released by you for this purpose to trustworthy companies for recruitment purposes. These companies use your data to consider you for job opportunities and to contact you. 

2.1.4 Dealing with the inventory data after the termination of the user contract 

After termination of the user contract iversity deletes your inventory data as long as iversity is not obliged to comply with retention periods prescribed by law, statutes or contracts rule out any erasure. If the latter is the case your data shall be blocked. 

**2.2 Usage data**

Via usage data iversity gains insights on how the Platform is used. Thus, iversity learns, e.g., which pages are the most popular and at what times the usage of the Platform particularly intense. iversity uses the results for technical and editorial improvements of the service.  
The IP addresses automatically collected by log files are anonymised and used if needed, in this anonymous form, for the improvement of the Platform and security reasons to be able to track abusive behavior of the service. You are entitled to object, at any point in time, to this kind of use of the log files via e-mail or by mail to the abovementioned addresses. In cases of such an objection iversity reserves the right to terminate the user contract according to the terms of use. A compilation of this data with other sources of data, particularly with the personal data of the User, is not performed. iversity reserves the right to inspect existing logs for the last known IP address of the User in case of a definite legal offence or contract violation by the User. This serves mainly to protect the Users of iversity and the security of User data on iversity.  
iversity uses Google Analytics to evaluate the use of the website in an anonymised way. Google may transmit this anonymised information to third parties if this is legally mandatory or if third parties are assigned from Google to process the data. In no way will Google associate your IP-address with other data of Google.  
The use of Google Analytics as well as the use of cookies not related to the login process is purely for statistical purposes. In doing so, iversity learns, e.g., which areas and content is accessed when and how. This information is used by iversity to design the Platform more comfortable for the Users. With the help of statistical results regarding the type of browser and operating system iversity is also able optimize the web design.  
iversity does not hand over usage data to third parties.  
After termination of the user contract iversity deletes your User data as long as iversity is not obliged to comply with retention periods prescribed by law, statutes or contracts rule out any erasure. If the latter is the case your data shall be blocked. 

**2.3 Content data**

You can publish information about yourself, your interests and other personal relationships on the Platform, especially in your profile and other pages which have been designed by you (e.g., your photos, articles, materials). Technically speaking, you transfer personal data via iversity as the technical provider of the Platform to third parties. However, you alone decide what kind of information you wish to share to which group of Users. Disclosing personal data enables other Users and visitors of the Platform to get to know you as well as giving you the opportunity to get in touch with other Users who you are interested in. iversity makes available the data you wish to be shared on the Platform technically. The profile you set up may be found via Internet search engines. However, you have the possibility to restrict the visibility of your profile by altering your privacy settings on the Platform. Under no circumstances will your e-mail address or your password be visible to the open Internet public or to other registered Users.  
We need the data about the courses you chose and the results of your exams to record and make available your progress to you. Furthermore, we need this data to award you with possible certificates for the participation or finalization of certain courses.  
Moreover, iversity transmits data (inventory and content data) released by you for this purpose to trustworthy companies for recruitment purposes. These companies use your data to consider you for job opportunities and to contact you. 

2.3.1 Matching 

iversity reserves the right to match User’s content on the Platform (e.g., contributions in discussion forums) with content published by other Users. Thus linking of content and people on the Platform is facilitated. This so-called "matching" is applied only to content which was explicitly published by the User and is solely intended to make relevant suggestions to you in a professional manner or to facilitate your search for relevant courses, individuals, events and contributions on the Platform. 

2.3.2 Apps 

iversity offers third party functionalities in the form of apps clearly marked as such. iversity is not responsible for these offers and does not have any active influence on them in any way. Any contracts resulting from third party apps are concluded only between the User and the third party, governed by the provisions of the respective provider. For further details regarding the data collection, data processing and data use by these services please refer to the respective data privacy policies of the respective provider. 

2.3.3 Dealing with the content data after the termination of the user contract 

After terminating your user contract, your profile, including the respective content will be deleted. Other content posted and not deleted by you on the Platform remains visible but will be anonymised or pseudonymized (e.g., the content is displayed without your name or your photo). This applies to uploaded content, communications and other interactions with Users. 

**3\. Links to Other Sites**

The websites of the Platform may contain links to other websites and services of providers which are not affiliated with iversity. After clicking on the links iversity has no influence on the processing of personal data which might have been submitted to third parties (such as the IP-address or URL that contains the link), since the behavior of third parties is beyond the control of the iversity. Therefore, iversity shall not be responsible for the processing of such personal data by third parties. 

**4\. Information, correction, erasure, blocking**

Upon written demand or in text form iversity will inform you which personal data of you is stored. You can also correct, block or delete your personal data at any time. To do so, please contact the following address: [datenschutz@iversity.org](mailto:datenschutz@iversity.org) or write us at the address mentioned above. For the right allocation of the request the following information have to be provided:  
Last name, first name  
E-mail address  
Address  
If you modify or correct personal information yourself, the personal data entered before is automatically deleted. Therefore, the easiest way for you to correct your data is to alter your records yourself.  
iversity advises you that deleted or corrected data may be visible for a few days after deletion due to caching systems and / or the interposition of proxy servers. Due to the obligation of iversity to ensure data availability, it is also possible that deleted or corrected data will be available after the deletion or adjustment for a limited period of time within the backups. This data is neither publicly visible nor processed any further or used in any other way.  
Excluded from deletion is data needed by iversity to process outstanding tasks or to enforce its rights and entitlements as well as data mandatorily to be preserved due to statutory provisions. However, such data shall be blocked.  
Should you have further questions about privacy on the Platform please contact the data protection officer who will be happy to help you. Simply write an e-mail to [datenschutz@iversity.org](mailto:datenschutz@iversity.org). However, please be patient if the question is not answered immediately on the following day. 

**5.Security**

iversity employs technical and organizational security measures to ensure that your personal data is protected against loss, incorrect alteration or unauthorized access by third parties. In any case, only authorized persons at iversity have access to your personal data and only insofar as it is necessary for the purposes mentioned above. 

**6\. Change of privacy policy**

iversity reserves the right to update this privacy policy. In the event of changes you will be informed with reasonable notice and asked to provide your necessary consent. 

Stand: Juni 2013
